Guide to the Camille Chautemps papers M1601
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series III: Publications/Manuscripts/Lectures
  - Articles
    - Camille Chautemps articles on French situation, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Camille Chautemps: Articles in Saturday Evening Post, 1942? 1944? (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Camille Chautemps: Articles on the Anschluss and defense of actions regarding 1942 and 1945 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Camille Chautemps: 'Temoignage'--Account of 1940 events, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Camille Chautemps: 'Temoignage'--Account of 1940 events, 1943 (second copy) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - "True Causes of the Drama of 1940" by Chautemps, 1946 (English translation) (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Unknown author: Notes on French situation during WWII, 1940-1944? (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Maret School Bilingual Magazine "Hand in Hand," in memoriam of Marthe Maret, 1944 (pp. 8-10 Chautemps' essay) (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Camille Chautemps: Letters to Winston Churchill and NYTimes editor, re: Churchill Memoirs, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - L'Echo de Touraine: "Une Lettre d'Amerique" par Camille Chautemps (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Camille Chautemps: Articles published in the "Courier de L'Ouest," 1951 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - L'Eclaireur Regional de l'Ouest: Deux discours par C. Chautemps, 1951 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Camille Chautemps: Articles in response to Reynaud's accusations, in NYTimes, undated and 1956 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Courier de l'Ouest: Articles on l'Affaire Kennedy and Eisenhower by Chautemps, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Camille Chautemps: Diary aboard S.S. Ile de France, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Courier de l'Ouest: Chronique L'Aga Khan, by Chautemps, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Gaullism: Notes of unknown provenance (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - "La Cinquieme Republique...": Handwritten article on its strengths and weaknesses (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - "Petain and the French fleet:" Article of unknown provenance (Box 14, Folder 35)
- Series IV: Biographical and Family History
  - Camille Chautemps
    - Short biographies of Camille Chautemps (copied excerpts from books) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Research paper of unknown author: "Between Pétain and DeGaulle: Camille Chautemps in the US--1940-45" (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Allard, Paul, From Les Favorites de la Troisieme Republique: "Les Amours Romantiques de C. Chautemps," 1942 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "Hommage a Jean Zay" with note from Camille Chautemps before leaving for US (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Camille Chautemps: Description of/bio for lecture tour, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Editorial from Le Cri de Paris (English translation), "Critic's Corner: The President Has the Floor," 1933 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Goins, Craddock article, "Drama in the News," re: Chautemps' visit to the news office, 1947? (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Releve de Comptes" accounts, 1946? (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Pension records, 1950s-1960s (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Camille Chautemps: Unidentified receipts for return of secret funds, Feb. 1940 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Camille Chautemps' US affidavit in lieu of passport, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - X-Ray of Camille Chautemps' arm and physician's reports (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Autograph book, program (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Camille Chautemps: Official documents, passports, etc. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Misc. documents (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - FBI files, Section 1(?), Jan. 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - FBI files, Section 2 (File 100-9023), Dec. 1941-Jan. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - FBI files, Section 3 (File 100-9023), Jan.-Feb. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - FBI files, Section 4 (File 100-9023), Jan.-Feb. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - FBI files, Section 5 (File 100-9023), Jan.-Mar. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - FBI files, Section 6 (File 100-9023), Jan.-Apr. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - FBI files, Section 7 (File 100-9023), Apr.-Jun. 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - FBI files, Section 8 (File 100-9023), May.-Sept. 1942 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - FBI files, Section 9 (File 100-9023), Jul.-Dec. 1942, 1943-47, 1952-54, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - FBI files: Obtained through administrative appeal (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - CIA documents (1941-1961): Obtained 1981 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - FBI, Dept. of State documents 1941-47, obtained in 1981 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - US Army Intelligence, Dept. of State surveillance documents, 1941-44 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Military intelligence memo re: Chautemps' relationship to Lemaigre-Dubreuil and post-war role in France, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Attorneys' correspondence, re: Release of FBI, CIA documents (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Freedom of Information Act inquiry by Antoinette in 1981 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Camille Chautemps: Filed FBI reports on, 1941-42 (photocopies) (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Photocopies of declassified US intelligence reports on French espionage and Chautemps in US, 1941-42 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Juliette Chautemps
    - Concert: Juliette Durand-Texte and Jacques Thibaud, clippings, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Millinery clippings, late 1940s, early 1950s (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Letters pertaining to Juliette Durand-Texte's (Chautemps) divorce from first marriage, 1933-1939 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Photos, postcard from Reynaldo Hahn, composer (to Juliette?), undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Letters pertaining to concerts, 1938-39 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Concert clippings, 1939-1940 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Letters of recommendation for Juliette Chautemps from her piano instructor, Alfred Cortot, June 1940 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Letter pertaining to establishment of US pianist career, 1941 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Concert clippings, 1941-43 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Concert letters, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Concert clippings, 1949-1950 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Clippings on becoming US citizen and father's visit to US, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Concert letters and clippings, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Juliette Chautemps concerts with Merson: Clippings, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Cover letter for a job application, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Funeral and obituaries, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Chautemps trial, 1947; Grant of amnesty in 1954
    - Camille Chautemps: Act of accusation, 1947 trial (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Annotated (by Antoinette?) copy of indictment from 1947 (English translation) (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Note sur l'application de l'art. 83 du code penal (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Camille Chautemps: Defense documents relating to trial, testimonies, etc., 1947 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Notes from NYTimes article, re: Sumner Welles' defense of Chautemps, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Camille Chautemps: Notes defending himself against trial accusations, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - High court verdict on Camille Chautemps, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Camille Chautemps: Press release following condemnation, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Chautemps letter of editor of unidentified journal, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Camille Chautemps: Miscellaneous documents relating to trial, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Camille Chautemps: Letter to Rene Malliavin ("Ecrits de Paris"), 1947 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Gift of monograph on injustices of end of war in France by Louis LaFaye, to Camille Chautemps (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Echo de Paris: (1) Michel Dacier's "Crime de Division," (2) Camille Chautemps' published response, "Lettre d'un Condamne" (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Camille Chautemps: Letters and documents leading up to amnesty, 1951-52 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Camille Chautemps: Formal docs and letters relating to amnesty, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Transcript of Chautemps trial, March 25, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Transcript of Chautemps trial, March 25, 1947 (annotated by Antoinette) (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Transcript of Chautemps trial, March 25, 1947 (incomplete) (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Various clippings for US and French press (photocopies), L'Affaire Chautemps (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Chautemps/Durand family history
    - Clippings re: Emile Chautemps (father of Camille) as mayor of Paris, Inauguration of Eiffel Tower, Statue of Liberty, 1889 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Genealogical documents of the Durand family (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Antoinette's notes on Chautemps' family history (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Research on Chautemps family history (sent to Antoinette from Jean?) (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Biographical info for Felix Chautemps (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Photo of Chautemps and his brothers as students at Lycee de Chartres (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Death of Claude Chautemps (son of Camille), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Division of Claude Chautemps' Estate, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Little Palace Hotel brochure: Square Emile Chautemps (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Antoinette Chautemps Samuels and Howard Samuels
    - Copy of warrant of arrest for Antoinette Chautemps, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of first communion, 1951 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Copies of clippings from Antoinette's younger years (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Antoinette Chautemps: Correspondence and clippings on starting acting career, 1940s (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Antoinette's debutante ball program, clippings, other invitations and news appearances, 1950s (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Antoinette Chautemps: International Azalea Court clippings, invitation, program, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Antoinette's debutante ball clippings, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Sidwell Friends graduation, report cards for Antoinette, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Letter from Ernesto to Camille Chautemps requesting permission to marry Antoinette and Chautemps' response, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Antoinette's graduation program from Georgetown University, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Antoinette's first marriage to John Bernard Sharkey, Jr., divorce (1965 and 1970) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - News article, "Loulette's Angry Crusade," 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Translation of Ma-Aariv article ft. interview of Antoinette by Arie Yass; also, Moshe Efrati Kol Demana dance company program (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Antoinette Samuels wins New Democratic Dimensions (NDD) Citizens' Achievement Award, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - NYTimes Magazine photocopied article by Gray: "The French: Portrait of a Country..." and Letters to Editor (incl. from Antoinette), 1985 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Antoinette as Executive Director of NY World Trade Council: Joint Venture Possibilities with France, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Liberty Week in France, Oct. 15-20, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - NY European heritage site proposal: Parc Europe, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Loulette Samuels statement for WMCA radio "View from the Torch" re: Statue of Liberty, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - La Nouvelle Republique: Article on Antoinette, "Une certaine Camille-Antoinette Chautemps," 1987 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - European American Heritage Foundation Incorporation, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Documents relating to screenplay: "With love, MM! The Life of Montrey McMurray" (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Midge Costanza with Caroline Elias: Drafts, notes for book, "The President's Woman" (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Notes for Midge Costanza's book, "The President's Woman" (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Samuels' Bridgehampton home? (undated photo) (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with realty company, re: Bridgehampton home, 1993 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Misc. letters to Antoinette (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Misc. documents and clippings belonging to Antoinette (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Article of unknown origin opposing 1972 re-election of Richard Nixon; in support of George McGovern (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, documents related to Antoinette's political activities, support for Democratic candidates (Gary Hart) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Booklet from Tantara, Peru commemorating la Semana Tantarina, includes printed letter from Sen. Ted Kennedy, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Sagg Bridge controversy in the Hamptons, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Thank you note from John (Neely?) Kennedy, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Antoinette Chautemps: Documents, clippings pertaining to support for Ted Kennedy (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Howard Samuels estate correspondence (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Funeral register for Howard Samuels (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - School memorabilia: (1) Camille's graduation from Duke, 1993, (2) Dominique's graduation program from Trinity, 1994, (3) Trinity phone directory (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Samuels family mementos: School art projects, cards from Howard to Loulette, report cards for Camille and Kiki (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Sketch portrait of Howard Samuels (Flat-box 25, Folder 2)
    - Aerial view of Samuels' Bridgehampton home (?) (Flat-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Howard Samuels clippings
      - Howard Samuels' campaign in NY gubernatorial race: Clippings, memorabilia, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Howard Samuels' NY gubernatorial campaign: Spanish newspaper clippings, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Clippings on Howard Samuels' election loss, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Howard Samuels' work with NASL and other clippings (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Clippings re: Howard Samuels' death, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Chautemps/Samuels Family Photographs
    - Unidentified photos, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Nicole, Jean, Claude Chautemps (?) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Paquita and Jack (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Camille Chautemps with various (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Camille Chautemps: Photos of, at official ceremony, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Germaine," 1941 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Photo portraits of Camille Chautemps (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Juliette Chautemps: Photos (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Juliette Chautemps and unidentified male (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - M. and Mme. Chautemps in US, late 1950s, 60s? (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Camille and Juliette with Jean Louis ("Mimi") and Antoinette, early 1950s? (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Camille Chautemps speaking, unidentified woman at same event (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Camille Chautemps and Antoinette (infant, young adult) (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Photo and layout map of Camille Chautemps' home in Loir-et-Cher as President du Conseil (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Antoinette Chautemps: Younger years (also, Jean Louis Bouquet) (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Antoinette Chautemps: Debutante (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Pictures taken by C. Chautemps: Graffiti, 'Assassin Chautemps' (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Antoinette's first marriage to John Bernard Sharkey, Jr., 1965 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Antoinette Samuels nee Chautemps (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Antoinette ("Loulette Samuels") Chautemps: Professional portraits (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Howard Samuels (1) with Antoinette, (2) at NASL soccer match in 1984, (3) with Gene Foley in 1975 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Lyndon B. Johnson and Howard Samuels (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - John F. Kennedy and Howard Samuels (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Jimmy Carter and Howard Samuels (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Signed photographs by Speaker Tip O'Neill with Antoinette and Howard Samuels (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Antoinette Samuels and Ted Kennedy, Jacqueline Kennedy (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Unidentified family photos, 2004-2005 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Negatives (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Camille Samuels and friends, 1973-75 (Box 18, Bound volume 1)
    - Samuels family, c. 1988 (Box 18, Bound volume 2)
    - Family pets (Box 18, Bound volume 3)
    - Photos of Camille and Dominique ("Kiki") Samuels, c. 1970s (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Proof sheets: Pictures of Antoinette's children (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Camille and Dominique ("Kiki") photos: granddaughters of Camille Chautemps (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Photograph of infant (Flat-box 25, Folder 1)
    - Aerial view of Samuels' Bridgehampton home (?) (Flat-box 25, Folder 3)
    - Proof sheets: Antoinette Samuels (Flat-box 25, Folder 4)
    - Artwork: Samuels family mementos, Mexico 1950 (Box 37, Folder 8)
- Series V: Antoinette Samuels' Biography of Camille Chautemps
  - Antoinette's reflections: "In Search of My Father" and incomplete synopsis (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Various drafts of Chapter 1 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Early draft of Chapter 2: Biographical sketch of Camille Chautemps and Chautemps family political dynasty (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Ch. 2: "Conversations with my Aunt" (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Book draft typescript: Chapters 1-8 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Book draft typescript: Chapters 2-12 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Chapters 9,10,12: Draft typescripts and copy (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Untitled chapter on the fall of France in June 1940 to Germany (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Unnamed section with TIME magazine excerpts showing US resistance to involvement in WWII despite Nazi threat (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Chapter entitled, "Exile years: Chevy Chase, 1940's," (two typescripts and copies) (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Draft typescripts of chapter entitled "The Trial: March 1947" (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Chapter entitled "May He Rest in Peace" (typescripts and copies) (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Chapter entitled "Ou est Papa?" and Epilogue (typescripts and copies) (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript: Prologue and First Chapter (French) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 1, Typescript draft (French) (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "A la Recherche de Mon Pere," Chapters 1-2 typescripts (French) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: Second chapter (French) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 2: Copy of Manuscript (French) (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Chapters 2-5, Typescript draft (French) (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Chapters 5-9, Typescript draft (French) (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Earliest outline (?), typescript copies (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Outlines: Chs. 1-17, some missing (typescript and copies) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Outline: Chs. 14-28, Epilogue (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Letter from Stuart Day of Image House Films re: Antoinette's biography of her father, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Loulette interview re: Camille Chautemps' life, by Arie Yass. Published in Ma Ariv? (English translation) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "Blurbs A,B,C:" Early drafts of book (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Early fragments (marked up) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - "N.B.": Note to Reader and note on C. Chautemps' career and A. Samuels' educational history (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Three spiral-bound ntoebooks containing Antoinette's notes for Camille Chautemps' biography (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Spiral-bound notebook with Antoinette's notes (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Research Materials
    - Notes on French history, 1914-1920s (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Outline of events from 1940-43 (by Jean Chautemps?) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Chautemps, Jean: Articles, clippings in defense of his father, 1946-47 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Interview Questions for Antoinette Chautemps from French researcher re: Camille's views on government (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Jean Chautemps: Correspondence, letters in defense of his father (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Letters from Jean Chautemps, Charles Pomaret, and Phillipe Kraemer-Raine defending Camille Chautemps (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Antoinette: Conversations with my Aunt, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Refugee Lists: "People my father saved"- Antoinette Samuels (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Antoinette's notes for book (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Materials from Samuels' campaign, re: allegations of Camille Chautemps' anti-semitism (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Materials from Samuels' campaign, re: allegations of Camille Chautemps' anti-semitism (cont'd) (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Photocopies of research materials (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Photocopies of research materials (cont'd) (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - William Shirer's book, "The Collapse of the Third Republic": index cards with notes and clippings of reviews (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Undated book reviews relating to books on Petain, French fascism, Auschwitz, Vichy government (Box 30, Folder 16)
- Series VI: Stavisky Affair
  - News report on Stavisky arrest, 1926 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Camille Chautemps: Memo and stats on activities of the financial section of the Parquet de la Seine, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Medical deposition re: Stavisky, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Financial Affairs inquiry, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - General Report on Stavisky Trial, 1931-34 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Pressard, Prosecutor General: Correspondence and meetings/hearings notes, 1930-34 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Letter to Chautemps, re: Affaire Prince, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Signed statement of support for Prosecutor General Pressard, April 1934 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Death of Pressard: Clippings, photos of deceased, funeral, Feb. 1935 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Camille Chautemps: Letters and documents, re: Pressard and his death (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Issue of Le Voltaire, re: Stavisky-Prince affaires (Chautemps cartoon on cover) (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Camille Chautemps: Misc. reports and memoranda of Prosector's office re: Stavisky and L'Abbe, 1934 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Camille Chautemps: Handwritten and typed notes, memoranda (incl. "Lettres de protestation a la commission d'enquete"), 1934-35 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Stavisky File: Handwritten list of relevant letters and documents from 1929-1932 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Notes, clippings on 1974 book, "Stavisky: les secrets du scandale," by Charlier and Montarron (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Jean Chautemps: Correspondence, clippings re: Affaire Prince, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Misc. book excerpts re: Stavisky affair, Chautemps' resignation (incl. 1979 "Le Cadran Solaire" by Philippe Lamour) (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Banque de France Submissions for Prosecutor-General Pressard, 1916 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Stavisky Affair documents (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Stavisky Affair documents (cont'd) (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Stavisky Affair Clippings
    - "L'Audition de M. Lescouve par la Commission D'Enquete Stavisky," Le Matin, April 11, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 13)
    - Affaire Peret: Clippings and documents, 1930-31 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Affaire Prince/Stavisky: Clippings pertaining to Chautemps and Frossard, 1934 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Affaire Stavisky: Chautemps deposition clippings, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Affaire Prince/Stavisky clippings (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "A la Commission Stavisky," Le Populaire, Feb. 21, 1935 (Flat-box 41, Folder 7)
    - "La deposition de Chevert devant la Commission Guernut: Stavisky connaisait depuis 1932 le conseiller Prince," L'Oeuvre, Nov. 7, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 8)
    - Elections & Jean Piot article on l'Affaire Prince, L'Oeuvre, October 8, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 6)
    - L'Affaire Prince-Stavisky (see also, connection with M. Laval), La Lumiere, Nov. 30, 1935 (Flat-box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Nouvelle deposition de M. Raymond Prince," L'Homme Libre, Dec. 20, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 11)
    - L'Oeuvre, Dec. 24, 1934 (incl. Stavisky investigation) (Flat-box 41, Folder 9)
    - L'Oeuvre, Nov. 9, 1934 (incl. Stavisky investigation) (Flat-box 41, Folder 10)
    - "Dans un expose lumineux et emouvant M. Camille Chautemps demontre que l'ascension de l'escroc fut anterieure a 1932," L'Oeuvre, Dec. 18, 1935 (Flat-box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Deuxieme partie de la deposition de M. Raymond Prince," Le Temps, Dec. 21, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Premiere partie de la deposition de M. Raymond Prince," Le Temps, Dec. 20, 1934 (Flat-box 41, Folder 17)